A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Correspondence Files FA1283
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Correspondence Files
1962-1991
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman
FA1283
31 Cubic Feet 71 document boxes, 1 oversized flat box, 1 oversized album case.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted.
Biographical / Historical
Laurance Spelman Rockefeller was born on May 26, 1910, in New York City, the fourth of the six children of Abby Aldrich and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. He attended the Lincoln School of Teachers College of Columbia University in New York before entering Princeton University in 1928. He graduated in 1932 with a B.A. degree in philosophy and went on to two years of graduate study at Harvard Law School.
On August 15, 1934, Laurance married Mary French in the Congregational Church in Woodstock, Vermont. Together they raised three daughters and a son. Laurance and Mary maintained homes in Manhattan and Pocantico Hills, New York; Jackson Hole, Wyoming; and Woodstock, Vermont.
During World War II, Laurance served in the U.S. Navy (1942-1945) in the Bureau of Aeronautics, attaining the rank of lieutenant commander.
Throughout his life, Laurance pursued a number of successful careers. He was a pioneer in the field of venture capital. He was an influential figure for three decades in the American conservation movement. He led the development of Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, one of the world's foremost cancer care and research facilities, and served as both a benefactor and advisor to major educational institutions. Laurance also combined his personal vision for conservation, recreation, and the spiritual needs of individuals to develop internationally acclaimed environmentally oriented resorts.
In 1935, he began working in the Family Office in Rockefeller Center. His first duties were to develop his knowledge of Rockefeller philanthropic activities, conservation projects, and business interests. Simultaneously, he developed his own interests, blending business acumen with the talents of a "gadgeteer," as he once referred to himself.
Laurance became well known as an investor of risk capital in young enterprises based primarily in scientific and technological development. Over the years his investment interests included the fields of aviation, aerospace, electronics, high temperature physics, composite materials, optics, lasers, data processing, thermionics, instrumentation, and nuclear power. Beginning in August 1969, his venture capital investments in these areas were made through Venrock, a venture capital group formed by members of the Rockefeller family. He also developed outstanding environmentally oriented resort hotels in Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Hawaii, and Vermont, serving as the chair of Rockresorts, Inc., a resort management company that he founded.
Conservation of the environment and recreational development constituted much of Laurance's philanthropy and public service. His introduction to public service came in 1939, when Governor Herbert Lehman of New York appointed him to the Palisades Interstate Park Commission (PIPC). He later served as president of the PIPC from 1970 to 1977 and continued as a commissioner until his resignation in December 1978.
While on a family vacation in 1926, Laurance had visited the region of Wyoming that includes Grand Teton National Park. Captivated by the area, his father subsequently purchased a substantial amount of land around Jackson Hole to safeguard it and the view of the Grand Teton Mountains. In 1949, as president of Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc., Laurance made a gift to the federal government on behalf of his father of the valley land, which was included in Grand Teton National Park.
Laurance established the American Conservation Association, Inc., in 1958 as a philanthropy to function as a conservation service agency, assisting the work of other agencies—both private and governmental—and initiating projects of its own. It was part of the movement that helped to focus public attention on the quality of the American environment.
Also in 1958, President Dwight Eisenhower appointed him chair of the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, which charted ways to meet the nation's outdoor recreation needs through the end of the century. He was a special emissary for President Lyndon Johnson in the effort that led to the creation of the Redwood National Park in California, and he served as chair of President Richard Nixon's Citizens' Advisory Committee on Environmental Quality, successor to a similar group that he headed under President Johnson. He played a pivotal role in the creation and development of several national parks including Grand Teton National Park in Wyoming; Virgin Islands National Park on the island of St. John; and Marsh, Billings, Rockefeller National Historical Park in Vermont.
Laurance served as a leader of several important nonprofit and philanthropic organizations. He was president and later chair of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund (1958-1980) and was a trustee of the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation (1960-1982). His first association with Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center was in 1947; he also served as chair (1960-1982), overseeing an expansion and modernization of its operations. He was a longtime trustee of the New York Zoological Society (1935-1986) and served as its president (1969-1971) and chair (1971-1985).
Laurance received many honors for his efforts on behalf of the environment and cancer research and treatment. Among them are the Alfred P. Sloan, Jr. Memorial Award from the American Cancer Society (1969), the Medal of Freedom (1969), the Congressional Gold Medal (1991), and the Lady Bird Johnson Conservation Award for Lifetime Achievement (1997). In 2003, he became the first person to be made an honorary citizen of the British Virgin Islands in recognition of his many contributions to the area.
Laurance Rockefeller died on July 11, 2004, at his home on Fifth Avenue in Manhattan.
Arrangement
The LSR Correspondence Files collection is arranged into five series: Series 1 - Alphabetical; Series 2 - Friends and Associates; Series 3 - Mail Log; Series 4 - Chronological Files; Series 5 - Special Letters.
Scope and Contents
The Correspondence Files collection of Laurance S. Rockefeller's papers, is comprised of alphabetical correspondence files for 1962-1991 from the LSR papers in the Rockefeller Family general files (record groups 3, 33, 37, and 39; and of LSR's files for individuals (Friends and Associates), pulled from these same general files. Sets of mail logs and chronological files, maintained by LSR's office from the early 1960s/early 1970s to around 1986, and two albums of "special letters" complete the collection.
While much of the correspondence is social in nature, the collection does help document LSR's personal and professional relationships, from longterm friends like Horace Albright to LSR's evolving interest in and support for spiritual ventures. The Friends and Associates series also partially documents LSR's working relationship with associates such as Clayton W. (Wes) Frye, Henry Diamond, and others.
- Correspondence - Alphabetical, 1962-1991; 1; 12 Cubic Feet 26 document boxes.
  Scope and Contents
  The Alphabetical Correspondence series contains LSR's personal correspondence files for the period 1962 - 1991, which originally formed part of LSR's papers in the Rockefeller Family general files, record groups 3, 33, 37, and 39. While there is much substantive correspondence in the files, a good portion of the materials consists of friendly notes and acknowledgment letters, social invitations, and condolence notes. The series also includes some interfiled general memos on everything from automobiles to dogs, skis, and security.
  Arrangement
  The Alphabetical Correspondence series consolidates four chronological sets of alphabetical files, arranged by name of correspondent. For the letters A - B only, the files have been integrated and arranged into a single alphabetical run. Beginning with the letter C, and for the rest of the series, the files are arranged alphabetically within each chronological segment, and consequently a correspondent may be found in successive files. The chronological divisions reflect the date ranges of the original record groups: 1962-1976, 1977-1981, 1982-1986, and 1987-1991.
  Restricted material, pertaining mainly to living members of the Rockefeller family, has been separated from its place in the alphabetical files and refiled at the end of this series.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - A (Abel - Astor), 1962-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - A (Astrological Charts - Auranieni), 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - A (Autograph Requests - Automobiles), 1962-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - B (Babbitt - Beattie), 1962-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - B (Bechtel - Bigham), 1962-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9 -10)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - B (Billings, Franklin S. and Polly), 1975-1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - B (Bissell - Boesky), 1962-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - B (Bogert, H. Lawrence and Margie), 1967-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - B (Boissonas - Boyer), 1962-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - B (Bracken - Byrnes), 1962-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15-19)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - C (Cagle - Choate), 1962-1976 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - C (Chorley, Kenneth and Jean), 1962-1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - C (Christen - Cushing), 1962-1976 (Box 4, Folder 23-26)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - C, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 27-29)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - C, 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - C, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - D, 1962-1976 (Box 5, Folder 34-36)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - D, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - D, 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 39-40)
    Henry Diamond correspondence in folder 39 includes his report on the American environmental delegation trip to the Soviet Union in June 1983.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - D, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - E, 1962-1976 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - E, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - E, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - E (East - West Center Foundation), 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    Includes material relating to the Dialogue of Civilizations project, established with funding from LSR and MFR.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - E, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - F (Fabian, Harold and Josephine), 1962-1976 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - F (Fanjul - Frye), 1962-1976 (Box 7, Folder 49-51)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - F (Fabian - Folk), 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - F (Forbes - Futscher-Pereira), 1977-1981 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - F, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - F, 1987-1991 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - G, 1962-1976 (Box 8, Folder 56-58)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - G, 1977-1981 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - G, 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - G, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - H (Haar - Hoving), 1962-1976 (Box 9, Folder 62-64)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - H (Howard - Huyler), 1962-1976 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - H, 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 66-67)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - H, 1982-1986 (Box 10, Folder 68-70)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - H, 1987 - 1991 (Box 11, Folder 71-73)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - I, 1962- 1991 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - J, 1962- 1976 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - J, 1977- 1981 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - J, 1982- 1986 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - J, 1987- 1991 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - K, 1962-1976 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - K, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - K, 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - K, 1987-1991 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - L, 1962-1976 (Box 12, Folder 83-85)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - L, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 86-87)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - L, 1982-1986 (Box 13, Folder 88-89)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - L (LaFarge - Lanier), 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 90-91)
    Correspondence with Sidney and Jean Lanier, 1988-1991, includes funding requests for New American Place and other programs.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - L (Lanin - Lynch), 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 92-93)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - M (MacArthur - Maze), 1962-1976 (Box 13, Folder 94)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - M (McAlpin - Murray), 1962-1976 (Box 14, Folder 95-96)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - M, 1977-1981 (Box 14, Folder 97-99)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - M (MacLaine - Mazlish), 1982-1986 (Box 14, Folder 100)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - M (McAlpin - Muzik), 1982-1986 (Box 15, Folder 101-102)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - M, 1987-1991 (Box 15, Folder 103-106)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - N (Naess - Nicklaus), 1962-1976 (Box 15, Folder 107)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - N (Nixon - Nusbaum), 1962-1976 (Box 16, Folder 108)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - N, 1977-1981 (Box 16, Folder 109)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - N, 1982-1986 (Box 16, Folder 110)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - N, 1987-1991 (Box 16, Folder 111)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - O, 1962-1976 (Box 16, Folder 112-113)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - O, 1977-1981 (Box 16, Folder 114)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - O, 1982-1986 (Box 17, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - O, 1987-1991 (Box 17, Folder 116)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - P, 1962-1976 (Box 17, Folder 117-118)
    Includes some correspondence pertaining to photos of LSR and photographers (e.g., at Jackson Hole Wildlife Park; Look Magazine images in 1969) (in folder 118, under "Photos").
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - P, 1977-1981 (Box 17, Folder 119)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - P, 1982-1986 (Box 17, Folder 120-121)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - P, 1987-1991 (Box 18, Folder 122-123)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Q, 1962-1991 (Box 18, Folder 124)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - R, 1962-1976 (Box 18, Folder 125-128)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - R (Randall - Riley), 1977-1981 (Box 18, Folder 129)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - R (Robb - Rutherfurd, 1977-1981 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - R, 1982-1986 (Box 19, Folder 131-133)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - R (Raines - Rockefeller), 1987-1991 (Box 19, Folder 134-135)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - R (Rodriguez - Rutherfurd), 1987-1991 (Box 20, Folder 136)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - S, 1962-1976 (Box 20, Folder 137-140)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - S (Sa'adah - Setzer), 1977-1981 (Box 20, Folder 141)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - S (Sexton - Swenson), 1977-1981 (Box 21, Folder 142-143)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - S, 1982-1986 (Box 21, Folder 144-147)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - S (Sacca - Shriver), 1987-1991 (Box 21, Folder 148-149)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - S (Sidamon-Eristoff - Subscriptions), 1987-1991 (Box 22, Folder 150)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - T, 1962-1976 (Box 22, Folder 151-153)
    Folder 151 includes correspondence with Cliff Taylor concerning the value of short skis for ski instruction, and includes a photo of Taylor, Eleanor Clark French, and LSR skiing at Mount Tom in 1965.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - T, 1977-1981 (Box 22, Folder 154-155)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - T, 1982-1986 (Box 22, Folder 156)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - T, 1987-1991 (Box 22, Folder 157)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - U, 1962-1981 (Box 22, Folder 158)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - V, 1962-1981 (Box 23, Folder 159)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - V, 1982-1991 (Box 23, Folder 160)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - W, 1962-1976 (Box 23, Folder 161-164)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - W (Wadsworth - Wessell), 1977-1981 (Box 23, Folder 165)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - W (White - Wright), 1977-1981 (Box 24, Folder 166)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - W, 1982-1986 (Box 24, Folder 167-169)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - W, 1987-1991 (Box 24, Folder 170 -172)
    Folder 168 includes correspondence and background material, 1986-1988, concerning Gunnar Wessman and various New Leaders initiatives.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - X-Y, 1962-1991 (Box 24, Folder 173)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Z, 1962-1991 (Box 24, Folder 174)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, David, Jr. and Diana N. Rowan Rockefeller, 1968-1994 (Box 25, Folder 175)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted. Materials in the Rockefeller Family collections pertaining to living members of the Rockefeller family are restricted.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D. IV, 1967-1991 (Box 25, Folder 176)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Stephen C., 1964-1991 (Box 25, Folder 177)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Aldrich, Hope, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 2A)
    Restricted. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that pertains to living members of the Rockefeller family is restricted.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - A (Astrological Charts), 1986 February (Box 25, Folder 5A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Broderick, Catharine Mauze O'Neill, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 15A)
    Restricted. Material in Rockefeller family collections that pertains to living members of the Rockefeller family is restricted.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Buden, Clare and James, 1982-1991 (Box 25, Folder 18A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Case, Everett, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 21A)
    Restricted. Case grandchildren (Laura Chasin children).
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Case, Peter, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 27A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Case, Jessica and Peter, 1984-1985 (Box 25, Folder 30A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Chasin, Dana and Julia, 1985, undated (Box 25, Folder 31A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Case, Matthew and Stacey, 1989-1991 (Box 25, Folder 32A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Dayton, Alida R., 1978 (Box 25, Folder 37A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Dulany, Margaret (Peggy) R., 1984 (Box 25, Folder 40A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Dulany, Margaret (Peggy) R., 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 42A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Ellison, Ingrid Rasmussen R., 1987 (Box 25, Folder 47A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Guion, Connie M., 1968 (Box 25, Folder 58A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Growald, Eileen, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 59A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Growald, Eileen and Paul, 1984-1986 (Box 25, Folder 60A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Goodwin, Neva; Eileen Growald; Rachel Gumina, 1987-1991 (Box 25, Folder 61A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Harris, T. George and Ann R., 1982 (Box 25, Folder 68A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Harris, T. George and Ann R., 1991 (Box 25, Folder 71A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Lyden, John and Carol, 1984-1986 (Box 25, Folder 89A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Lyden, John and Carol, 1988-1991 (Box 25, Folder 93A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Morgan, Mary R., 1977, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 99A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Morgan, Mary R., 1986 (Box 25, Folder 102A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Morgan, Mary R., 1987-1991 (Box 25, Folder 106A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Nolan, Jennifer and John Philip, Jr., 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 111A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - O'Neill, Abby (Gail), 1975 (Box 25, Folder 112A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - O'Neill, Abby (Gail), 1981 (Box 25, Folder 114A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - O'Neill, Abby (Gail), and George D. O'Neill, Jr., 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 115A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Caulkins, Abby (Gail) O'Neill; Abby M. O'Neill, George D. O'Neill, Jr., Peter O'Neill, 1987-1991 (Box 26, Folder 116A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Pierson, Mary Louise, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 119A)
    Restricted. Material in the Rockefeller Family collections that pertains to living members of the Rockefeller family is restricted.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Pierson, Mary Louise, and Clare Pierson, 1982-1984 (Box 26, Folder 121A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Pierson, Joseph, and Mary Louise Pierson, 1987-1991 (Box 26, Folder 123A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Rockefeller (General), 1962-1976 (Box 26, Folder 127A)
    Restricted. Alida Rockefeller, 1971; Margaret (Peggy) Rockefeller, 1970; Meile Rockefeller, 1973; Michael Rockefeller, 1962; Neva Rockefeller, 1964, 1972.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Rockefeller (General), 1977-1981 (Box 26, Folder 130A)
    Restricted. Alida Rockefeller, 1978; Eileen Rockefeller, 1978-1981; Larry Rockefeller, 1977-1978; Nelson A. Rockefeller, Jr., 1979, undated; Stuart Rockefeller, 1980.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Rockefeller (General), 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 133A)
    Restricted. Ann R. Roberts, 1982, 1986; Larry and Wendy Rockefeller, 1983-1985; Mark Rockefeller, 1983-1984; Meile Rockefeller, 1983, 1986; Michael S. Rockefeller, 1986; Nelson A. Rockefeller, Jr., 1981-1986; Peter C. Rockefeller, 1986; Steven C. Rockefeller, Jr., 1982-1986; Stuart A. Rockefeller, 1986.
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Roberts, Ann R., 1990 (Box 26, Folder 134A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Rockefeller (General), 1987-1991 (Box 26, Folder 135A)
    Restricted. Ingrid Rockefeller, 1987; Larry and Wendy Rockefeller, 1989-1990; Margaret (Peggy) Dulany Rockefeller, 1988-1990; Mark and Nelson A. Rockefeller Jr., 1987-1991; Peter C. and Allison Rockefeller, 1989-1991; Rodman and Sascha Rockefeller, 1987-1989; Steven C. Rockefeller, Jr., 1988-1991
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Spencer, Hope, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 140A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Spencer, Benjamin, and Hope Aldrich, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 147A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Spencer, Benjamin, David H. Spencer, and Theodore Spencer, 1987-1990 (Box 26, Folder 150A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Growald, Eileen R., 1987 (Box 26, Folder 160A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Waletzky, Lucy R., and Marion R. Weber, 1982-1985 (Box 26, Folder 167A)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical - Waletzky, Lucy R.; Yiguan and Wendy Wang; Rachel and Marion R. Weber, 1988-1991 (Box 26, Folder 170A)
- Friends and Associates, 1962-1991; 2; 11.4 Cubic Feet 26 document boxes, 1 oversized flat box.